Guide to the Institute for Defense and Disarmament Studies Records, 1974-2007.
Institute for Defense and Disarmament Studies Records
- “US and Soviet Nuclear Forces in the 1980s: Un uncontrolled Arms Race, Moderate Arms Control or a Nuclear-Weapons Freeze?” By Randall Forsberg, 1980-11 (Box 20, Folder 66)
- "Ellsworth Air Force Base, South Dakota: A prime Nuclear Target" by Randall Forsberg, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 67)
- “The Structure of US Military Spending” by Randall Forsberg, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 68)
- "Call to Freeze the Nuclear Arms Race" by Randall Forsberg, 1982-03-21 (Box 20, Folder 69)
- Stop the Arms Race!, Christianity and Crisis, 1981-11-25 (Box 20, Folder 70)
- Symposium at Harvard, 1986-09-05 (Box 20, Folder 71)
- “Military policy obstacles to Disarmament”, 1981-08-05 (Box 20, Folder 72)
- “The Obstacles to a Stable Disarmed Peace and How to Set Our Priorities to Overcome Them”, 1984-06-17-1984-06-19 (Box 20, Folder 73)
  Address by Randall Forsberg to Kiel Week Congress “God’s Peace to All People”
- “A Practicable, Medium-Term Program for Working toward Disarmament” by Randy Forsberg, 1978-06-21-1978-08-17 (Box 20, Folder 74)
- "Budget-cutting as a Toll of Disarmament" by Randall Forsberg, 1978-05-03 (Box 20, Folder 75)
- Military policy, 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 76)
  Includes “USSR is not ahead” original draft
- Overall Assessment of the START Proposal by Randall Forsberg, 1982-05-11 (Box 20, Folder 77)
- Hearings and testimonies and FAS journals, 1982-11 (Box 20, Folder 78)
- The Case for a Nuclear-Weapon Freeze, 1982-03 (Box 20, Folder 79)
  Prepared for a congressional debate with R. Burt
- “Stopping the Nuclear Arms Race” by Randall Forsberg, 1983-01-13-1983-01-15 (Box 20, Folder 80)
- “Defining and Implementing the Freeze”, Outline of Workshop by Randall Forsberg, 1983-02-05 (Box 20, Folder 81)
- Statement by Randall Forsberg at the Midwest Freeze Rally, Chicago, 1984-10-13 (Box 20, Folder 82)
- Randall Forsberg Address 20th Anniversary March on Washington, 1983-08-27 (Box 20, Folder 83)
- National and Regional Initiatives for Disarmament, 1983-05-11-1983-05-13 (Box 20, Folder 84)
- Nuclear Power and Nuclear Weapons, Critical Mass Conference, 1978-10-06 (Box 20, Folder 85)
- Some Ideas for Creating An Effective Disarmament Movement, 1978-10-17 (Box 20, Folder 86)
  SIPRI/MIT/American Peace Directory, IWO meeting
- Copies of Publications about the FREEZE and Randy Forsberg, Date unknown (Box 20, Folder 87)
- “Theory proposed which might ease threat of war” by Randall Forsberg, 1987-11-03 (Box 20, Folder 88)
- Original “Deterrence vs. Disarmament” by Randall Forsberg, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 89)
  Submitted to NYT, not published
- Original “Call to Halt Nuclear Arms Race” by Randall Forsberg, 1979-12-19 (Box 20, Folder 90)
- Original “Nuclear Imperialism” by Randy Forsberg, 1979-09 (Box 20, Folder 91)
- “Nuclear Weapons and the Permanent War Economy” by Randall Forsberg, 1979-09 (Box 20, Folder 92)
- “A Zero-Based Approach to the FY 1980 Military Budget" by Randall Forsberg and George Sommaripa, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 93)
- A Peace-Movement-Wide “No New Nuclear Weapons” Campaign to Stop the US-Soviet Nuclear Arms Race by Randy Forsberg, 1979-11 (Box 20, Folder 94)
- World Military RandD and Control of the Technological Arms Race, 1978-10-10 (Box 20, Folder 95)
- Current Manufacturing and Deployment of US Nuclear Weapon Systems, 1979-01 (Box 20, Folder 96)
- Letter to the Editor, 1982-10-25 (Box 20, Folder 97)
- Testimony of Randall Forsberg, 1983-02-17 (Box 20, Folder 98)
- Testimony of Randall Forsberg, 1982-04-01 (Box 20, Folder 99)
- Prepared Statement of Randall Forsberg at the Harvard Symposium on Beyond Deterrence, 1982-04-01 (Box 20, Folder 100)
- Hearing on Strategic Arms Control and U.S. National Security Policy, 1982-05-11 (Box 20, Folder 101)
- Randall Forsberg’s testimony at the “Women for a Meaningful Summit”, 1987-12-04 (Box 20, Folder 102)
- IDDS Press Release, “START Proposal Invites a Continued Arms Race” by Randall Forsberg, 1982-05-10 (Box 20, Folder 103)
- “A Nuclear Weapons Freeze and A Non-Interventionary Conventional Policy”, Nuclear Disarmament Conference, 1980-09 (Box 20, Folder 104)
- Photocopy of Randall Forsberg’s Article “A Nuclear Freeze and a Noninterventionary Conventional Policy”, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 105)
- Photocopy of the article “End and Nuclear Weapons Freeze” by Matthew Evangelista, Randall Forsberg and Mark Niedergang, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Randy’s Article: “Worldwide Arms Cuts Are Possible”, 1979-03 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Randy’s Article: “Opportunities for Reducing U.S. Arms”, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Randy’s Article: "Disarmament Needs Strong Public Support", 1979-12 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- “Military RandD: A Worldwide Institution?” by Randall Forsberg, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- “The Case Against A Rapid Deployment Force”, Opinion by Randall Forsberg, 1980-06-03 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- “Women and Military Policy-Making”, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  Article based on a speech delivered by RF at Bernard College on November 4, 1983
- Photocopy of the Article: "What’s Happening to Our Country?" By Randall Forsberg, Undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
- “Call to Freeze Nuclear Arms Race”, Original WFUNA Bulletin, No: 21, 1982-03 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- “Stop the Arms Race” by RF, 1982-01-18 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- JFK School of Government Bulletin, “Beyond Deterrence: Avoiding Nuclear War in the longer run", 1987 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- "Parallel Cuts in Nuclear and Conventional Forces” by Randall Forsberg, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 12)
- “Is a US-Soviet Nuclear-Weapons Freeze Possible?” By Randall Forsberg, 1980-08 (Box 21, Folder 13)
- "The Economic and Social Costs of the Nuclear Arms Race" by Randall Forsberg, 1981-03-02 (Box 21, Folder 14)
- RF statement before NGO Committee on Disarmament, UN Third Special Session, 1988-06 (Box 21, Folder 15)
- “Randall Forsberg on the Freeze”, Interview in the River Valley Voice, 1983-05 (Box 21, Folder 16)
- “Roundup on Press Coverage on INF” by RF and Chalmers Hardenbergh, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 17)
- “What about a Nuclear Freeze?” By Randall Forsberg, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 18)
- RF published works, Undated (Box 21, Folder 19)
- “Conventional Stability and Confidence Building Structure” Loccumer Protokolle, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 20)
- Joint Works: American Priorities In a New World Era, World Policy Institute Publication, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 21)
- “The Case for a Bilateral Nuclear Freeze” by RF and other publications related to Freeze, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 22)
- “Hands of Pacts Reduce Nuclear Threat” by Randall Forsberg, 1987-10-06 (Box 21, Folder 23)
- “We have to leave the past to prevent nuclear war” Harvard Symposium, 1987-09-25 (Box 21, Folder 24)
- IDDS papers, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 25)
- “A defensively oriented route to disarmament” by Randall Forsberg, 1983-11 (Box 21, Folder 26)
- The Distribution of World Military Funds by Region and Purpose, Main results, Undated (Box 21, Folder 27)
- Trip to USSR, Spring 1981 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  Contains statement by Randall Forsberg “To the Soviet Peace Committee and to the Soviet Press”
- Contain materials related to Randy Forsberg trips and talks at different places in the U.S and abroad, 1981-1982 (Box 21, Folder 29-48)
- Original, first IDDS brochure, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 49)
- Original, early letterhead, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 50)
- IDDS publications list, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 51)
- Press questionnaire, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 52)
- IDDS brochure drafts, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 53)
- Original IDDS brochure drafts/projects, Undated (Box 21, Folder 54)
- Portfolio press materials, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 55)
- Freeze articles in major newspapers, 1982-03-1982-04 (Box 21, Folder 56)
- Media/IDDS Press Conferences, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 57)
- Original, plus 1 copy of the paper: “Confining the Military to Defense as a Route to Disarmament” by Randall Forsberg, 1984-06 (Box 21, Folder 58)
- “Confining” reprint inventory, Undated (Box 21, Folder 59)
- “A Defensively-Oriented Route to Disarmament by Randall Forsberg”, 1983-11 (Box 21, Folder 60)
  Draft with staff comments
- “A Defensively-Oriented Route to Disarmament" by Randall Forsberg, 1983-11-07 (Box 21, Folder 61)
- Booklet of pictures and speeches, 1981-04-25 (Box 21, Folder 62)
  Support of a Mutual US-USSR Arms Freeze
- "The Freeze and Beyond, Confining the Military to Defense as a Route to Disarmament", Winter 1984 (Box 21, Folder 63)
- Randy Forsberg articles, reprints, correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 64)
- Institute for Policy Studies, The Arms Race and Nuclear Weapons – A research project, 1981-12 (Box 21, Folder 65)
  Proposal for funding, William M. Arkin, Fellow
- Copy of Freeze and Beyond in World Policy Journal, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- “Confining” Reprints, costs, title, ordering info, Date unknown (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Comments/ critiques of “confining” article, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- “The Deadly Connection” book correspondence, 1985-03-19 (Box 22, Folder 4)
- 744 Scientific American Offprints: A Bilateral Nuclear-Weapons Freeze, by Randall Forsberg, 1982-1983 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  Original copy, includes related correspondence
- “Confining” reprint, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Draft of "A Defense-Oriented Route to A Stable, Disarmed Peace" by Randall Forsberg, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Proposal for Base Support, 1981-03 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Judith Reppy’s copy of the Program and Notes from 25th Anniversary Symposium for IDDS and Nuclear Freeze, 2005-10 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- APD: endorsers, Undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
- APD: reviews, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Donahue mailing, 1984-06 (Box 22, Folder 12)
- Unidentified material, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 13)
- Guide: nuclear weap. Freeze, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 14)
- Freeze voter resumes, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Kaplan, Jeremiah, Undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
- Originally unidentified loose material, Date unknown (Box 22, Folder 17-21)
- Print copies of the Arms Control Reporter, 2001, 2006, 2007 (Box 22)
- Tape cassettes of talks by Randall Forsberg, 1982-1986 (Box 23)
- Tape cassettes of talks by Randall Forsberg, 1985-1990 (Box 24)
- Print copies of the Arms Control Reporter, 1982-1987 (Box 25)
- Print copies of the Arms Control Reporter, 1988-1994 (Box 26)
- Print copies of the Arms Control Reporter, 1995-2000 (Box 27)